Guide to the Dept. of Landscape Architecture records, 1898-1959.
Dept. of Landscape Architecture records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dept. of Landscape Architecture records, 1898-1959.
15-2-1622
Cornell University.Department of Landscape Architecture.
1.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, design problems, scrapbook, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence and material relating to the College of Architecture and the Department of Landscape Design.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence; memoranda; reports; student design problems used in fellowship competitions of the American Academy in Rome; curricula and other materials relating to Cornell design courses; College of Architecture scrapbook; photographs and negatives of faculty, students, design models, and buildings; copies of blueprints; and sketches. Also, materials pertaining to Eugene D. Montillon, Gilmore D. Clarke, Edward Lawson, and others in the Department of Landscape Design.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Clarke, Gilmore D., 1892-1982.; Lawson, Edward.; Montillon, Eugene D.; American Academy in Rome.; Cornell University.College of Architecture--Curricula.
Subjects:
Architecture.; Landscape architecture.
Form and Genre Terms:
Architectural drawings.; Negatives.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., January 1931-July 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., August 1931-December 1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., January 1932-November 1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., December 1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., January 1937-May 1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., June 1937-December 1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., January 1952-March 1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., April 1952-June 1952 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., July 1952-December 1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., January 1953-April 1953 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., May 1953-December 1953 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1954 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., January 1956-May 1956 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., June 1956-December 1956 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., January 1957-May 1957 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., June 1957-December 1957 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., January 1958 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., January 1958-December 1958 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1898-1909 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1909-1912 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1912-1915 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- College of Architecture correspondence, memoranda, reports., 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Design Problems., 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- American Academy in Rome, fellowship competitions., 1920-1936 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- American Academy in Rome, fellowship competitions., 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Binghamton City Planning Study., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Reports on College of Architecture., 1941-1959 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Statistics., 1907-1917 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Miscellaneous., no date (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Miscellaneous., no date (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Miscellaneous., 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Edward Lawson, Planting Design Course #650., no date (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Planting Design Course #650, student sketches., 1930-1934 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Plaque commemorating Engineer's Day Chairmen of the College of Architecture., 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- "Landscape Architecture, Cornell University, History of the School.", 1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Materials pertaining to Eugene D. Montillon's work of the history of Landscape Architecture at Cornell., 1917 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Eugene D. Montillon materials concerning education of landscape architects., 1921 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Eugene D. Montillon correspondence with Dilmore D. Clark concerning landscape instruction., 1930 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Eugene D. Montillon correspondence with Dilmore D. Clark concerning the American Society of Landscape Architects., 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Eugene D. Montillon correspondence with Dilmore D. Clark concerning the American Academy in Rome fellowship competition., 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Eugene D. Montillon correspondence and drafts concerning the Landscape Architecture Department at Cornell., 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Eugene D. Montillon study: "Two Degrees, Six Years.", 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Eugene D. Montillon: Landscape Construction Course #660., 1936-1942 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Eugene D. Montillon history of Landscape Design notes., no date (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Association of Professional Schools of Landscape Architecture minutes and reports, Eugene Montillon's Report to the Faculty., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Students Drawings Account - Various articles/offprints on architecture, 1919-1920 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Photographs of faculty and students; copies of blueprints and photographs of buildings and models; sketches., no date (Box 3)